James Schmiechen github.com/JFschmiechen

ifschmiechen@gmail.com | (661) 546-3979 | California | ifschmiechen.github.io

SKILLS & INTERESTS

- Skills: React.js, Java, GraphQL, Node.js, Express, Firebase, Apollo, Redux, Python, Numba, Numpy, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Electron, MaterialUI, Semantic UI, Antd, Sass, Agile, CMS
- Interests: Game of Thrones, CRPGs, cooking, computer vision, Medieval games/history

SUMMARY

Self-motivated, independent, and resourceful full-stack developer with four years of experience building complex web applications. I am focused on front end development with a passion for creating pleasing UI/UX experiences using React and CSS preprocessors. I am always looking to expand my skillset and learn more.

WORK EXPERIENCE

OnStack Software 2017 - 2018

React Developer

Bakersfield, CA

- Implemented Redux with React to construct a case management system, using Redux's predictable state container and React's reusable components to slash case processing time by 50%.
- Built API using Express and GraphQL to distribute cases and users, utilizing GraphQL's typed schema and optimized queries to efficiently propagate data to the front end and maintain HIPAA compliance.
- Discussed project viability, mock ups, and time estimates with clients.

Bakersfield College 2018 - 2019

Software Engineer

Bakersfield, CA

- Used Java to create a health equity platform, utilizing Java's cross compatibility and open source libraries to improve health equity for thousands of disadvantaged minorities.
- Utilized React, Firebase, and Google Analytics to construct a CMS providing comprehensive usage metrics, user management, and automated chat moderation.
- Self-started to completion a secure firebase API that interfaces with both third-party APIs and the app itself.
- Lead Jr. developers to learn the ins and outs of coding and contribute on a real-world project.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

React event calendar (React.js)

2019

- Used MaterialUI and React to develop a modern, configurable, and modular event-based calendar component.
- Dynamically scales to fit any viewport as well as any space on a web page with a unique mobile view.
- Downloaded and used in over 350+ projects a week.

Custom edge detection algorithm (Python)

2018 - Present

- Used Python to create edge detection algorithm modeled after the receptive field of retinal ganglion cells.
- Detects edges in 1920 x 1080 image in 0.56 seconds (Fastest time, N = 1000).

Ifschmiechen.github.io (React.js)

2017 - Present

- Uses the Ant design library and React to create a professional and clean user experience.
- Features responsive design preserving page structure and style in any view port.
- Implements google analytics to track usage metrics.

EDUCATION

San Francisco State University

2021

Bachelors, Computer Science

San Francisco, CA 2019

Bakersfield College

Associates, Computer Science

Bakersfield, CA